Robert E. Sherwood Play Scripts
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Robert E. Sherwood Play Scripts 1921-1962
MSS39818
Sherwood, Robert E. (Robert Emmet), 1896-1955
34 items
3 containers
1.2 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Dramatist. Typescripts of plays by Sherwood submitted for copyright to the Library of Congress Copyright Office.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Sherwood, Robert E. (Robert Emmet), 1896-1955.
Subjects
Drama--Stories, plots, etc.
Titles
Robert E. Sherwood papers; Robert Emmet Sherwood papers
Occupations
Dramatists.
Provenance
The play scripts of Robert E. Sherwood, dramatist, were transferred to the Manuscript Divison from the Library of Congress Copyright Office in 1981.
Restrictions
Restrictions apply governing the use, photoduplication, or publication of items in this collection. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division for information concerning these restrictions. In addition, many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Robert Emmet Sherwood was born April 4, 1896, in New Rochelle, N.Y. Sherwood was a playwright, editor, screen writer, and cofounder of the Playwrights’ Company, a producing company. He wrote speeches for President Franklin D. Roosevelt during World War II and from 1941 to 1944 served as head of the overseas branch of the Office of War Information. Sherwood’s book Roosevelt and Hopkins (1948) won the Pulitzer Prize, as did several plays, including The Road to Rome (1927) and Abe Lincoln in Illinois (1938). His original screenplay, The Best Years of Our Lives, won the Academy Award in 1946. Sherwood died in New York, November 14, 1955.
Scope and Content Note
The play scripts of Robert Emmet Sherwood (1896-1955) span the years 1921-1962 and are dated according to the year the typescripts of dramas were submitted for copyright to the Library of Congress Copyright Office. Titles begin with The Dawn Man (1921) and include The Road to Rome (1926), Abe Lincoln in Illinois (1937), Miss Liberty (1949), Small War on Murray Hill ( 1953), and Champagne and Caviar (1957), an adaption by Eddie Davis and Sam Alper of Sherwood’s English version of Jacques Deval’s Tovaritch.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged by year of submission and therein by title of play.
Container List
- 1921, The Dawn Man (Box 1)
- 1926 (Box 1)
  - The Love Nest (Box 1)
  - The Road to Rome (Box 1)
- 1927, Marching as to War (Box 1)
- 1928, The Queen's Husband (two copies) (Box 1)
- 1929 (Box 1)
  - Horse-Shoes (Box 1)
  - Waterloo Bridge (Box 1)
  - Wooden Wedding (Box 1)
- 1930 (Box 1)
  - Happy Days (Box 1)
  - It's a Bargain (Box 1)
  - This Is New York (Box 1)
- 1931, Reunion in Vienna (Box 2)
- 1932, Acropolis (Box 2)
- 1933, Afterglow (Box 2)
- 1934 (Box 2)
  - Milk and Honey (Box 2)
  - The Petrified Forest (Box 2)
- 1935 (Box 2)
  - Idiot's Delight (Box 2)
  - Tovaritch, by Jacques Deval, English adaptation by Sherwood (Box 2)
- 1937, Abe Lincoln in Illinois (Box 2)
- 1945 (Box 2)
  - Out of Hell (Box 2)
  - The Rugged Path (Box 2)
- 1949, Miss Liberty (Box 3)
- 1951, Girls with Dogs (Box 3)
- 1952, The Better Angels (Box 3)
- 1953 (Box 3)
  - The Backbone of America (Box 3)
  - The Trial of Pontius Pilate (Box 3)
  - Small War on Murray Hill (Box 3)
- 1954 (Box 3)
  - The Days before Revolution (Box 3)
  - Dear Diary (Box 3)
  - Fear of God (Box 3)
- 1957, Champagne and Caviar, by Eddie Davis and Sam Alper, adaptation of Sherwood's English version of Jacques Deval's Tovaritch (Box 3)
- 1962, Waterloo! by Douglas Marland, adaptation of Sherwood's Waterloo Bridge (Box 3)